

Phone: 760-822-2626

Website:

alec-y-cheng.github.io

Vanderbilt graduate ('24) with a B.S. in Architecture & the Built Environment and a B.S. in Cognitive Studies. Experienced in academic writing, design thinking, design software, GIS research methods, and data visualization. Challenge-driven, adaptable, skilled in service, communication, and management. Unique design perspective due to multifaceted degree combination and diverse work experiences.

EXPERIENCE

May 2024 — August 2024

Barge Design Solutions PLANNING INTERN

Worked as a full-time intern for several urban landscaping and planning projects under a goal-oriented mentorship. Designed document booklets for potential clients, created informative maps to visualize land use patterns, researched zoning codes, played a key role in the design of new, resilient plans, and engaged with the community via public meetings and workshops. Collaborated with architects, transportation planners, environmentalists, and engineers

December 2023 — Present

GRID Design Journal *EXECUTIVE MEMBER*

Write, manage, conduct outreach, and interview guests for an academic architecture and design journal. Work in a team to seamlessly integrate pioneering discourses on the built environment engaged by students, architects and academics into a comprehensive journal issue

October 2023 — June 2024

Vanderbilt Institute for Spatial Research RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Involved in historical preservation work of Andrew Jackson's Hermitage site and William Edmondson's Homesite. Georeferenced and imposed old site drawings onto current satellite imagery. Met regularly with project directors to discuss expectations for deliverables. Developed mastery over GIS tools and deliverable design

Summer 2023

Harvard GSD Design Discovery PARTICIPANT

Accepted into and participated in an intensive, hands-on 3 week course in architectural design thinking, processes, and software. Designed a building from site analysis to final model that preserves an East Boston site's historical legacy while expanding it to suit modern demands

EDUCATION

Class of 2024 Early Graduation

Vanderbilt University, Nashville

BS in Architecture and the Built Environment, BS in Cognitive Studies. Focus in architectural history, urban planning, public policy, GIS methods. GPA: 3.97, Magna Cum Laude

AWARDS

May 2024

Outstanding Graduate in Architecture & the Built Environment

Awarded by the Vanderbilt History of Art/Architecture department to recognize the most outstanding graduate in the major. Chosen by faculty decision and included a \$500 award

December 2021 — May 2024

Peabody Scholars Program

Selective honors program (16 students per cohort) for those engaged in community service and education. Helped design a new website and logo for a local non-profit

Summer 2023

Western Mongolia Archaeology Project

Received a \$6000 stipend by the Peabody Scholars Program to survey, excavate, and catalog the archaeological origins of Bronze Age peoples in the Asian Steppes

ACTIVITIES

October 2022 — May 2024

Vanderbilt Architecture Society

Attended lectures, social events, and firm tours to explore the architecture field and connect with students pursuing similar paths

March 2023 — May 2024

Peabody Academic Mentor

Planned freshman orientation and events to guide students through first year challenges

SKILLS

C, Python, MS Office, Adobe Suite, Revit, Blender, Rhino, QGIS/ArcGIS, Laser Cutting, 3D Printing